Harold Spivacke Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1943-1971, undated, (2 boxes) (Box 28, 33)
  - Miscellaneous. Notebook of music for violin and piano see also Writings, Violin lecture-recitals, Copyist's manuscript in ink and pencil (Locatelli is the one exception); Laid in: Notes; 2 p.; Contents: Baltzer, Thomas. Allemande für Violine allein, undated; 1 p. Brade, William. Der alte Hildebrand, 1617; 2 p. Fontana, Giovanni Battista. Balletto, 1641; 2 p. Locatelli, Pietro Antonio. IV Caprice, 1733; 2 p. (Negative photostat) Pesenti, Martino. Corrente, 1645; 3 p. Torelli, Giuseppe. Konzert für Violine and Streichorchester, undated; 1 p. Uccellini, Marco. Corrente seconda, 1695; 3 p. Veracini, Antonio. Sonata for violin, violone and cembalo, 1696; 4 p. Vitali, Giovanni Battista. Cappriccio secondo, 1689; 3 p. (Box 28/9)
  - O'Hara, Geoffrey, and Irwin Rowan. Sons and daughters of a land reborn. New York: [s.n.], 1949, Printed choral score; 10 p.; Inscribed by the composer. (Box-folder 28/10)
  - Powell, Mel. Sweet lovers love the spring, undated, Photocopy of copyist's manuscript, choral score; 13 p.; Above title: "to Martha." (Box-folder 28/11)
- Printed Matter, 1929-1977, undated, (3 boxes) (Box 14-16)
  Articles, books, bulletins, newsletters, journals, pamphlet, and student handbooks.
  Arranged alphabetically by author, place or format.
  - Berlin State Library, undated, Pamphlet (Box 14/5)
  - Bulletins / Newsletters, A-M, 1942-1977 (Box 14/6)
  - Bulletins / Newsletters, N-Z, 1933-1977 see also Correspondence, National Music Council; Realia, National Music Council; Photographs, Photoprints, Spivacke with Others (Box 14/7)
  - Castaneda, Carlos. "The beginning of printing in America," undated, Article; Inscribed and signed by author. (Box 14/8)
  - Collins, J. Lawton. War in peacetime, 1971, Book; Inscribed and signed by author. (Box 15/1)
  - Dallapiccola, Luigi. "Words and music in Italian XIX century opera," 1964, Article; Inscribed and signed by author. (Box 15/2)
  - Duckles, Vincent. "General plan for a history of music by Dr. Charles Burney with a catalogue of his musical library," 1972, Article (Box 15/3)
  - Faber, A. W. "Castell" Präzisions-Rechenstäbe, 1930, Booklet (Box 15/4)
  - Finkelstein, Herman. "The composer and the public interest—Regulation of performing right societies," 1954, Article; Inscribed and signed by author. (Box 15/5)
  - Finkelstein, Herman. "The copyright law—A reappraisal," 1956, Article (2 copies); Inscribed and signed by author. (Box 15/5)
  - "F-K" miscellaneous, Inscribed and signed by authors. (Box 15/8)
  - Ginastera, Alberto, William Shand, and Alberto Girri. Beatrix Cenci, 1971, Libretto (Box 15/6)
  - Ginastera, Alberto and Manuel Mujica Láinez. Bomarzo, 1966-1967, Libretto; Inscribed by Ginastera. (Box 15/7)
  - "L-O" miscellaneous, Some inscribed and signed by authors. (Box 15/9)
  - Mann, Thomas. "The theme of the Joseph novels," 1942, Address (Box 15/10)
  - Mann, Thomas. From the book of Genesis, Joseph the provider, undated, Pamphlet (Box 15/10)
  - Menus from restaurants, 1929 and undated, Printed in German. (Box 15/11)
  - Passing through Germany, 1928/1929, Book (Box 15/12)
  - "R-S" miscellaneous, Inscribed and signed by authors. (Box 15/13)
  - Toscanini Memorial Archives, undated, Pamphlet (Box 15/14)
  - University of Berlin catalogs and student handbooks, 1929-1930 (Box 16/1)
  - University of Berlin catalogs and student handbooks, 1930-1933 (Box 16/2)
  - "W" miscellaneous, Inscribed and signed by authors. (Box 16/3)